A romantic comedy. With zombies.
Shaun of the Dead is a horror, comedy film directed by Edgar Wright.
Shaun lives a supremely uneventful life, which revolves around his
girlfriend, his mother, and, above all, his local pub.
This gentle routine is threatened when the dead return to life and
make strenuous attempts to snack on ordinary Londoners.
Shaun, played by Simon Pegg.
Ed, played by Nick Frost.
Liz, played by Kate Ashfield.
Dianne, played by Lucy Davis.
David, played by Dylan Moran.
Yvonne, played by Jessica Hynes.
Shaun of the Dead is a 2004 British zombie comedy film directed by
Edgar Wright and written by Wright and Simon Pegg.
Pegg stars as Shaun, a downtrodden London salesman who is caught
alongside his loved ones in a zombie apocalypse.
It also stars Nick Frost in his film debut, Kate Ashfield, Lucy
Davis, Dylan Moran, Bill Nighy, and Penelope Wilton.
It is the first film in Wright and Pegg's Three Flavours Cornetto trilogy,
followed by Hot Fuzz (2007) and The World's End (2013).
Shaun of the Dead was inspired by ideas Pegg and Wright used for their 1999–2001 television sitcom
Spaced, particularly an episode in which Pegg's character hallucinates a zombie invasion.
The film references the Night of the Living Dead films by George A.
Principal photography took place across London and at Ealing
Studios for nine weeks between May and June 2003.
Shaun of the Dead premiered in London on 29 March 2004, before it was theatrically released in
the United Kingdom on 9 April 2004 and in the United States on 24 September.
It was met with critical acclaim and commercial success, grossing $38.7 million worldwide on a budget
of $6.1 million and receiving three nominations at the British Academy Film Awards.
It was ranked third on the Channel 4 list of the 50 Greatest
Comedy Films and quickly acquired a cult following.
In film studies, it is seen as a product of post-9/11 anxiety and a model for transnational comedy, while the
zombie outbreak as depicted in the film has been used as a modelling example for disease control.
The film explores themes of london, england, dark
comedy, satire, surrey, parody.
The tone is lighthearted and dark and intense.